Arch Oboler Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 9. Scripts, 1933-1993 and undated, 70 linear feet (168 boxes)
  - Stage, film, television, circa 1938-1993 and undated
    - New ideas, unfinished, 1941 June-1960 June (Box 338, Folder 2)
    - "Night"
      - circa 1980-1989 (Box 338, Folder 3)
      - Edie Adams version, undated (Box 338, Folder 4)
    - Nightmare series, fire and town files, 1942 April (Box 338, Folder 5)
    - "Of Human Bondage," a television treatment, undated (Box 338, Folder 6)
    - "The Old Boy"
      - Television version, circa 1987 (Box 338, Folder 7)
      - Arch Oboler's Plays version, with a television version, 1939, undated (Box 338, Folder 8)
      - Contracts and correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 338, Folder 9)
      - Oboler's scriptbook for television version, 1960 August (Box 338, Folder 10)
      - "The Old Boy" set blueprints (Arch Oboler Time), 1960 August (Box OS 1, Folder 10)
      - San Diego State College and television versions, 1965 April (Box 339, Folder 1)
      - Shooting script for the Arch Oboler show, 1960 August (Box 339, Folder 2)
      - Television treatment, 1979 (Box 339, Folder 3)
      - Television proposal and research document, 1979 (Box 339, Folder 4)
      - Television synopsis, 1973 (Box 339, Folder 5)
    - "Only Woman in the World"
      - Fire file, 1941 August-1950 April, undated, (3 folders); (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box 339-341, Box 339, Box 340, Box 341)
      - Town file, 1941 July, 1943 October, 1946 March, undated, (2 folders) (Box 341-342, Box 341, Box 342)
    - "Ostrich in Bed"
      - Television, fire file, 1949 September (Box 342, Folder 3)
      - Television, town file, 1949 September (Box 342, Folder 4)
    - "Point a Fiery Finger," film synopsis, 1975 (Box 343, Folder 1)
    - "Poofie" synopsis, undated (Box 343, Folder 2)
    - Prison play information, 1950 May-1958 June (Box 343, Folder 3)
    - "Projective Mr. Drogan," loose page with edits, 1969 (Box 343, Folder 4)
    - "Putty Cat," 1967 (Box 343, Folder 5)
    - "Rajah," television treatment and synopsis, undated (Box 343, Folder 6)
    - "'Rape Room,' A Synopsis for Television," undated (Box 343, Folder 7)
    - "Rebel in Concrete," draft with corrections, circa 1980-1989 (Box 343, Folder 8)
    - "Revolt of the Worms," 1987 television version, circa 1987 (Box 343, Folder 9)
    - "Rocket from Manhattan," television version, circa 1987 (Box 343, Folder 10)
    - "Screechers"
      - 1974 treatment, circa 1974 (Box 343, Folder 11-12)
      - Motion picture synopsis, undated (Box 343, Folder 13)
      - Screenplay, undated (Box 343, Folder 14)
    - Scripts for Jackie Gleason, circa 1957 (Box 343, Folder 15)
    - Scripts sent to Steven Spielberg care of Polly Rose, 1984 November (Box 344, Folder 1)
    - "Seven Dreams," 1957 September-1961 March (Box 344, Folder 2)
    - "Sokolove Revue," ideas for television, circa 1970-1979 (Box 344, Folder 3)
    - "Speak of the Devil," a special for television, undated (Box 344, Folder 4)
    - Spear in the Sand
      - circa 1950-1954 (Box 344, Folder 5-6)
      - Draft with corrections, circa 1950 (Box 344, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence with Raoul C. Faure, 1949-1953 (Box 344, Folder 8)
        Faure authored the novel Spear in the Sand, on which Oboler's proposed 3-D film was based. The film was never made.
      - Location notes started January 26, 1954, 1953 October-1954 February (Box 344, Folder 9)
    - "Special to Hollywood"
      - Fire file, 1940 February, 1941 February, 1945 July, 1964, (1 folder) (Box 344-345, Box 344, Box 345)
      - "Special to Hollywood (Fly High)," circa 1973 (Box 345, Folder 2)
      - "Special to Hollywood (Fly High)," town file, undated (Box 345, Folder 3)
      - Enright draft, 1980 (Box 345, Folder 4)
      - Town file, 1940 February, 1941, 1945 July, 1964 January (Box 345, Folder 5-6)
      - Television brochure, circa 1970 (Box 345, Folder 7)
      - Loose pages, undated (Box 345, Folder 8)
      - Movie, fire file, 1942 September, undated (Box 345, Folder 9)
      - Television series, 1958, town file, circa 1958 (Box 346, Folder 1-2)
    - Strange Holiday
      Written by Oboler and originally intended for employees of General Motors, this was the first film he directed.
      - 1952 March-1953 April (Box 346, Folder 3)
      - Town file, 1944 August (Box 346, Folder 4)
      - Movie, fire file, 1944 July, November (Box 346, Folder 5-6)
    - "Subway"
      - Town file, 1960 February-September, undated, (3 folders); (4 folders) (Box 346-347, Box 346, Box 347)
      - Movie/novel, town file, 1960 February-March, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 347-348, Box 347, Box 348)
    - "Surprise," undated (Box 348, Folder 2)
    - Synopses for television series, town file, 1957 August (Box 348, Folder 3)
    - Television market contact list, 1970 April (Box 348, Folder 4)
    - Television pilot ideas, circa 1981 (Box 348, Folder 5)
    - Television series proposal, 1973 (Box 348, Folder 6)
    - Three story lines for That Girl, circa 1970 (Box 348, Folder 7)
    - "This Lonely Heart"
      "...the Tchaikovsky story for Bell Telephone Hour."
      - 1960 November 25 (Box 348, Folder 8-9)
      - Record for Decca, Bette Davis, town file, undated (Box 348, Folder 10)
      - Television, town file, 1960 November, 1962 April, (1 folder) (Box 348-349, Box 348, Box 349)
    - "This Precious Freedom"
      Made as a short film in 1942.
      - First movie, fire file, 1942 August (Box 349, Folder 2)
      - Movie, town file, 1942 July (Box 349, Folder 3-4)
      - Set blueprint, 1942 July 23 (Box OS 1, Folder 11)
    - "Three by Oboler"
      - Art Carney and Jackie Gleason, for television, undated (Box 349, Folder 5)
      - Fire file, undated (Box 349, Folder 6)
      - Robinson, television, fire file, undated (Box 349, Folder 7)
      - "Three by Oboler: A Special for Television," undated (Box 349, Folder 8)
    - Three plays for Love American Style, circa 1970 (Box 350, Folder 1)
    - "The Trail," television script, Murray, town file, 1939 September (Box 350, Folder 2)
    - "The Trial of Dr. Watson"
      - A television treatment, fire file, undated (Box 350, Folder 3)
      - A television treatment, town file, undated (Box 350, Folder 4)
    - TV play ideas, 1964-circa 1989 (Box 350, Folder 5)
    - Television series, 1958
      - "Across the Gap," 1957 August (Box 350, Folder 6)
      - "African Story," circa 1958 (Box 350, Folder 7)
      - "Baby," 1957 August (Box 350, Folder 8)
      - "Bathysphere," circa 1958 (Box 350, Folder 9)
      - "Big Shot - Masculine," circa 1958 (Box 350, Folder 10)
      - "Bon Voyage," 1957 August (Box 350, Folder 11)
      - "Cat Wife," circa 1958 (Box 350, Folder 12)
      - "Chickenheart," circa 1958 (Box 350, Folder 13)
      - "The Chinese Gong," circa 1958 (Box 350, Folder 14)
      - "Dog's Eye View," 1957 August (Box 350, Folder 15)
      - "The Dream," 1957 August (Box 350, Folder 16)
      - "Eigerwund," 1957 August (Box 350, Folder 17)
      - "He Dug It Up," 1957 August (Box 350, Folder 18)
      - "Him or Me," circa 1958 (Box 350, Folder 19)
      - "History of a Mug," circa 1958 (Box 350, Folder 20)
      - "I Have No Prayer," 1957 August (Box 350, Folder 21)
      - "The Immortal Gentleman," 1957 August (Box 350, Folder 22)
      - "Lady Napoleon," circa 1958 (Box 350, Folder 23)
      - "Marriage 1957," circa 1957 (Box 350, Folder 24)
      - "Mirage," circa 1958 (Box 350, Folder 25)
      - "Mr. Tcitizen," circa 1958 (Box 351, Folder 1)
      - "Mr. Ten Percent," circa 1958 (Box 351, Folder 2)
      - "Mr. Vegas," 1957 April-1958 March, 1965 October (Box 351, Folder 3-4)
      - "Mr. Vegas," synopsis and characters, 1957 April-1958 March (Box 351, Folder 5)
      - "Mrs. Kingsley's Report," circa 1958 (Box 351, Folder 6)
      - "My Chicago," 1957 August (Box 351, Folder 7)
      - "Night," circa 1958 (Box 351, Folder 8)
      - "Of Human Bondage," 1957 August (Box 351, Folder 9)
      - "The Old Boy," circa 1958 (Box 351, Folder 10)
      - "Pay the Piper," 1957 August (Box 351, Folder 11)
      - "Poison Pen," 1957 August (Box 351, Folder 12)
      - "Poltergeist," 1957 August (Box 351, Folder 13)
      - "Projective Mr. Drogan," circa 1958 (Box 351, Folder 14)
      - "Revolt of the Worms," 1957 August (Box 351, Folder 15)
      - "This Living Book," 1957 August (Box 351, Folder 16)
      - "The Trial of Dr. Watson," 1957 August (Box 351, Folder 17)
      - "Vicious Circle," circa 1958, (1 folder) (Box 351-352, Box 351, Box 352)
      - "Visitor from Hades," 1958 (Box 352, Folder 2-3)
      - "Wonderful Day," circa 1958 (Box 352, Folder 4)
      - "Wonderful World," circa 1958 (Box 352, Folder 5)
    - Television, some under 15 minutes, 1956, undated (Box 352, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified loose pages, "Penny and Boy," undated (Box 352, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified stage play, partial, undated (Box 352, Folder 8)
    - Unnamed Fox television series, includes "Saga of Helga," circa 1970 (Box 352, Folder 9)
    - View '75, 1975 (Box 352, Folder 10)
    - Visitor from Hades, circa 1970 (Box 352, Folder 11)
    - "Wake Up Screaming: Three Plays for Television," circa 1987 (Box 352, Folder 12)
    - "The Way Is Clear," stage play, town file, 1943, 1944 January (Box 353, Folder 1-4)
    - Way Out
      - An outline for a motion picture in Space-Vision, undated (Box 353, Folder 5)
      - Town file, circa 1960-1969 (Box 353, Folder 6)
      - Television series proposal, 1965 (Box 353, Folder 7)
      - Warner's television series proposal, undated (Box 353, Folder 8)
    - "What the Devil"
      - "What the Devil," "Come to the Bank," undated (Box 353, Folder 9)
      - Motion picture for television, circa 1981-1989 (Box 353, Folder 10)
      - A trio of the amazing, for television, undated (Box 353, Folder 11)
      - For Rod Serling, 1960 (Box 353, Folder 12)
        The script was purchased but never produced as an episode of Serling's television series, The Twilight Zone.
      - Promotional pieces for television, circa 1981-1989 (Box 354, Folder 1-3)
      - Proposal for television series, 1985 February (Box 354, Folder 4)
      - Stage play, 1958 (Box 354, Folder 5)
      - Teleplay, undated (Box 355, Folder 1)
      - Revisions for Rod Serling, undated (Box 355, Folder 2)
      - Stage play, 1958 March, May-1960 April (Box 355, Folder 3-4)
      - "What the Devil: A Play about Ghosts," 1958 (Box 355, Folder 5)
      - Twilight Zone, fire file, 1963 June (Box 355, Folder 6)
      - Television, including Twilight Zone, town file, circa 1963 (Box 355, Folder 7)
    - "Willow's Ark"
      - 1963 (Box 355, Folder 8)
      - undated (Box 356, Folder 1)
      - Play for television, 1979 February (Box 356, Folder 2)
      - Retyped version, 1967 August (Box 356, Folder 3)
    - "Wonderful Day," television treatment, town file, 1958 (Box 356, Folder 4)
    - "Wonderful World"
      - Television treatment, fire file, undated (Box 356, Folder 5)
      - Television treatment, Murray, town file, undated (Box 356, Folder 6)
    - "The Word"
      - Movie treatment, town file, 1950 October, 1964 (Box 356, Folder 7)
      - Synopsis, circa 1981-1989 (Box 356, Folder 8)
        Includes pages from script "Beware" and notations regarding ready-made tapes for syndicated radio.
    - World We Love
      - Television special, 1974 (Box 356, Folder 9)
      - Television series proposal and contract, 1974 (Box 356, Folder 10)
- Series 10. Catalog File, 1941-1969, 2.5 linear feet (6 boxes)
  Oboler evidently maintained several filing systems for his personal and business records, which he variously identified as Catalog, Ranch, Town, and Fire files. The Catalog File series consists mainly of personal financial records, including household bills, automotive expenses, and travel expenses. However, there are also Catalog File materials on Oboler’s motion picture activities, including proposals and financial papers. The topical range of materials in the Catalog File is typical of many of Oboler’s miscellaneous paper accumulations.
  The original arrangement of the Catalog File, roughly alphabetical by subject or correspondent, and chronological within folder, is retained, though this arrangement has certainly been disrupted over time by rehousing and moving of the materials.
  - Bills paid (ranch), 1941-1969
    - New building, ranch: welding, 1963 November-1965 April (Box 357, Folder 1)
    - New house air conditioner, 1955 August-1963 (Box 357, Folder 2)
    - New house auto, 1954 June-1957 January (Box 357, Folder 3)
    - New house bomb shelter, 1957 September-1962 February (Box 357, Folder 4)
    - New house building material, 1954 January-1963 April (Box 357, Folder 5)
    - New house concrete, 1953 December-1968 August (Box 357, Folder 6)
    - New house construction work, 1954 August-1955 February (Box 357, Folder 7)
    - New house electrical, 1955-1967 (Box 357, Folder 8)
    - New house equipment, 1952-1968 (Box 357, Folder 9-11)
    - New house equipment repair, 1954 February-1963 October (Box 358, Folder 1)
    - New house fire equipment, 1955 February-1959 September (Box 358, Folder 2)
    - New house glass, 1955 March-1960 November (Box 358, Folder 3)
    - New house hardware, 1954 August-1965 October (Box 358, Folder 4)
    - New house, Harry Shaw, 1954 February-1965 October (Box 358, Folder 5)
    - New house interiors, 1954-1965 (Box 358, Folder 6)
    - New house Japanese garden, 1963 March-1966 February (Box 358, Folder 7)
    - New house labor, 1954 January-1958 October (Box 358, Folder 8)
    - New house lumber, 1954-1962 (Box 358, Folder 9)
    - New house miscellaneous, 1954 October-1967 April (Box 358, Folder 10)
    - New house paint, 1951 June-1959 September (Box 358, Folder 11)
    - New house plumbing, 1941 August-1965 November (Box 358, Folder 12)
    - New house pool, 1954 January-1966 March (Box 358, Folder 13)
    - New house professional service, 1954 January-1956 February (Box 358, Folder 14)
    - New house pumps, 1953 May-1957 October (Box 359, Folder 1)
    - New house rental, 1952 November-1967 July (Box 359, Folder 2)
    - New house roofing, 1954 December-1957 March (Box 359, Folder 3)
    - New house steel, 1954 December-1958 March (Box 359, Folder 4)
    - New house wells, 1958 February-1964 September (Box 359, Folder 5)
    - Ranch equipment, 1966 November-1969 February (Box 359, Folder 6)
    - Ranch garden, 1964 April-1965 May (Box 359, Folder 7)
    - Bills paid, and correspondence concerning the new building (ranch) and Southern California Edison, 1955 October-1962 September (Box 359, Folder 8)
    - Building Department correspondence, new house, 1954 December-1959 June (Box 359, Folder 9)
    - Dam, new building, 1955 August (Box 359, Folder 10)
    - New building invoices, 1955 January-February (Box 359, Folder 11)
    - New building receipts, signs, 1959 July-1966 June (Box 359, Folder 12)
    - Ranch instructions, diagrams, 1956 September (Box 359, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous requests concerning the ranch, 1960 May (Box 359, Folder 14)
  - European trip information and catalogs, 1949-1967
    - Switzerland, 1953 September-December (Box 359, Folder 15)
    - Italy catalogs, 1953 September and undated (Box 359, Folder 16)
    - France, 1953 January-August (Box 359, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 1949 October-1967 September (Box 359, Folder 18)
    - Norway, 1953 May-1954 June (Box 359, Folder 19)
    - Sweden, 1951-1954 August (Box 359, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous, 1952-1958
    - Auto information and catalogues, 1952 February-1954 March (Box 359, Folder 21)
    - Government, 1953 February-March (Box 359, Folder 22)
    - Index to file, undated (Box 359, Folder 23)
    - Ranch filing, 1954-1958 (Box 359, Folder 24)
  - Motion picture data, 1947-1969
    - Lumia-Wilfred, 1947 June-1959 April (Box 359, Folder 25)
    - Advertising, 1962 June-1965 March (Box 359, Folder 26)
    - Budgets, 1951-1959 (Box 359, Folder 27)
    - Motion picture code, 1954 March (Box 359, Folder 28)
    - Copyright search, 1967 March (Box 360, Folder 1)
    - Distribution information, 1952 December-1965 March (Box 360, Folder 2)
    - Equipment, 1951-1966 (Box 360, Folder 3-6)
    - Equipment: catagators and snowmobiles, 1965 May-1966 April (Box 360, Folder 7)
    - Europe, 1952 October-1953 August (Box 360, Folder 8)
    - Film stock, 1954 May-1966 January (Box 360, Folder 9)
    - Location possibilities, 1952 April-1967 (Box 360, Folder 10)
    - Material file, 1960 June (Box 360, Folder 11)
    - News, 1960 June (Box 360, Folder 12)
    - Possible investors, 1954 May-1965 July (Box 360, Folder 13)
    - Motion picture references, undated (Box 360, Folder 14)
    - Research (catalog file), undated (Box 360, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous services, 1952 September-1965 (Box 360, Folder 16)
    - Sound equipment, 1953 February-1967 April (Box 361, Folder 1-2)
    - Still shots, undated (Box 361, Folder 3)
    - Studios, 1954 May-1969 April (Box 361, Folder 4-5)
    - Title information, 1950 June-1958 July (Box 361, Folder 6)
    - Canned music, 1965 and undated (Box 361, Folder 7)
    - Film labs, 1953 June-1968 July (Box 361, Folder 8)
    - Kline free properties, 1956 April-1957 September (Box 361, Folder 9)
    - Possible employees, 1952 December-1967 May (Box 362, Folder 1)
    - Publicity, 1967 June (Box 362, Folder 2)
  - Personal bills paid, 1948-1968
    - Accounting, 1958 August-1960 August (Box 362, Folder 3)
    - American Airlines, 1953 May-1965 August (Box 362, Folder 4)
    - Advertising, 1958 December-1963 November (Box 362, Folder 5)
    - African Adventure, 1950, 1948 May-1953 March (Box 362, Folder 6-7)
    - Employees, 1960, 1960 May-1965 October (Box 362, Folder 8)
    - "1st Pregnant Man," 1964 July-1968 February (Box 362, Folder 9)
    - Kinsey movie, 1958 August-1960 September (Box 362, Folder 10)
    - Lefkowitz & Co., 1954 October-1965 March (Box 362, Folder 11)
    - Legal, 1953 March-1962 December (Box 362, Folder 12)
    - Merrill Granger, 1960 March-1965 May (Box 362, Folder 13)
    - Preview theater, 1960 December-1966 January (Box 362, Folder 14)
    - Trade magazines, 1960 February-1964 April (Box 362, Folder 15)
    - Unions, 1956 March-1966 September (Box 362, Folder 16)
    - Duell, Sloan & Pearce and Decca Records, African Adventure, 1949 February-1957 July (Box 362, Folder 17)
    - Burrelle's, 1953 April-1954 February (Box 362, Folder 18)
    - Capitol Records, 1962 November-1963 October (Box 362, Folder 19)
    - TV brochure, 1957 October-1958 December (Box 362, Folder 20)
- Series 11. Sound Recordings, 1938-1987 and undated
  The collection contains approximately 107 7-inch and 10-inch Mylar and acetate sound tape reels; 124 analog audiocassettes; 1 12-inch and 2 10-inch aluminum-based lacquer discs; and 1 12-inch vinyl transcription disc. The recordings consist mainly of episodes from Oboler radio series such as Lights Out, Plays for Americans, Everything for the Boys, and Everyman's Theater, but there are also announcements, sound effects, and music from some of his motion pictures, as well as radio compilations, demos, and outtakes.
  Also included in the collection but not yet processed are approximately 785 unpublished flexi discs (sound sheets) of various sizes and colors, including Edison Voicewriter and Gray Audograph discs; 20 audiocassettes that are as yet unidentified; and 12 commercial 8-track tape cartridges.
  For more information about the sound recordings and their availability for listening purposes, please contact the Recorded Sound Reference Center, Library of Congress, Washington, DC, 20540-4690; (202) 707-7833; http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mbrsrs/mbrsrs.contact.
Separated Materials
Selected items were transferred from the Recorded Sound Section to other custodial divisions of the Library of Congress in 2008 and 2009:
Over 300 architectural drawings, most of them by Frank Lloyd Wright of the Oboler home in Malibu, California, along with 19 maps, 17 slides of the Oboler children, and a stereoscopic viewer, were transferred to the Library of Congress Prints and Photographs Division. A preliminary catalog record is available for these materials at URL http://www.loc.gov/pictures/item/2009633260/. For additional information, see http://www.loc.gov/rr/print/address.html
Multiple 35mm and 16mm film rolls, including some nitrate films, were transferred to the Moving Image Section of the Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress. For details, see http://www.loc.gov/rr/mopic/mphours.html
Numerous scores were transferred to the Library's Music Division. See the Performing Arts Reading Room contact information page at http://www.loc.gov/rr/askalib/ask-perform.html
Twenty maps and land plats, chiefly of Arch Oboler's property in Malibu, California, were transferred to the Library's Geography and Map Division. For details, see http://www.loc.gov/rr/geogmap/contact.html
Some of the books originally included in the collection were transferred to the Library's General Collections.